It will scare you to your very soul.
Angel Heart is a horror, mystery film directed by Alan Parker.
A down-and-out Brooklyn detective is hired to track down a singer on an odyssey that will take him through the desperate streets of
Harlem, the smoke-filled jazz clubs of New Orleans, and the swamps of Louisiana and its seedy underworld of voodoo.
Harry Angel, played by Mickey Rourke.
Louis Cyphre, played by Robert De Niro.
Epiphany Proudfoot, played by Lisa Bonet.
Margaret Krusemark, played by Charlotte Rampling.
Ethan Krusemark, played by Stocker Fontelieu.
Toots Sweet, played by Brownie McGhee.
Angel Heart is a 1987 neo-noir psychological horror film, an
adaptation of William Hjortsberg's 1978 novel Falling Angel.
The film is written and directed by Alan Parker, and stars Mickey
Rourke, Robert De Niro, Lisa Bonet and Charlotte Rampling.
It is an international co-production between the United
Kingdom, the United States and Canada.
Harry Angel (Rourke), a New York City private investigator, is hired to solve the
mysterious disappearance of a singer known as Johnny Favorite.
His investigation takes him to New Orleans, where he
becomes embroiled in a series of brutal murders.
Following publication of the novel, Hjortsberg began developing the screenplay for a film
adaptation, but found that no major studio was willing to produce his script.
The project resurfaced in 1985 when producer Elliott
Kastner brought the book to Parker's attention.
Parker began work on a new script and made
several changes to Hjortsberg's novel.
He also met with Mario Kassar and Andrew G.
Vajna, who agreed to finance the $18 million production through
their independent film studio Carolco Pictures.
Filming took place on-location in New York City and New Orleans, with
principal photography lasting from March to June 1986.
Weeks before its theatrical release, Angel Heart faced ratings issues from the
Motion Picture Association of America for one scene of sexual content.
Parker was forced to remove ten seconds of footage to avoid an X rating and secure
the R rating that the film's distributor Tri-Star Pictures wanted.
An unrated version featuring the removed footage
was later released on home video.
Angel Heart received a mixed reaction from reviewers, who praised the performances of Rourke and Bonet, as
well as the production design, score and cinematography, but criticized Parker's screenwriting.
The film underperformed at the North American box office, grossing $17.2 million during its
theatrical run, but has since been regarded as underappreciated and influential.
The film explores themes of new york city, amnesia, heart, southern usa, voodoo.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.